Finding Aid for Arthur W. Kramer sound recording collection, 1958-1965
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Arthur W. Kramer sound recording collection 1958-1965
Kramer, Arthur W., 1906-1998.
2 linear feet
2009039 Aa 2
Tape recordings of speeches by conservative and anti-communist lecturers.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was received in 2008 from the Labadie Collection of the University of Michigan Library (donor 1180 ).
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Arthur W. Kramer (1906-1998) was an Ypsilanti, Michigan, police officer. Beyond this, nothing is known about the origin of the collection.
The collection contains tape recordings (7" and some 5" reels) of speeches by conservative and anti-communist lecturers. Most of the tapes are dated, and are arranged by year.
Subjects - Sound Recordings:
Anti-communist movements--United States.; Anti-communist movements--Michigan.
Contributors: Sound recordings
Anderson, Tom, 1910-; Arens, Richard.; Bouscaren, Anthony Trawick.; Brown, Julia Clarice.; Bundy, Edgar C.; Burke, Albert E.; Davidow, Larry.; Decatur, Catherine.; Dodd, Bella V., 1904-1969; Dodd, Thomas J. (Thomas Joseph), 1907-1971.; Dunker, Stephen.; Edwards, William J.; Fagon, Myron.; Friedman, Benjamin.; Greene, Janet.; Hallinan, Vincent.; Hoover, J. Edgar (John Edgar), 1895-1972.; Hunter, Edward, 1902-1978.; Ingram, H. Robert.; Judd, Walter Henry, 1898-1994.; Kershner, Howard Eldred, 1891-1990.; Koch, Fred C.; Lesinski, T. John.; Lewis, Fulton, 1903-1966.; Mandel, William M.; Mayer, William E., 1923-; McIntire, Carl, 1906-2002.; Millin, Leslie.; Morris, Robert.; Noble, John F.; Philbrick, Herbert A. (Herbert Arthur), 1915-1993.; Pittman, Carter.; Prussion, Karl.; Rousselot, John H.; Schlafly, Fred.; Schlafly, Phyllis.; Siegrist, Bob.; Schwarz, Fred, 1913-; Skousen, Cleon.; Sluis, Jost.; Stone, Willis E. (Willis Emerson), 1899-; Strube, William P.; Thurmond, Strom, 1902-2003.; Vaus, Jim.; Ward, Chester Charles.; Wheeler, Basil.; Wilkinson, Frank, 1914-2006
Genre Terms:
Sound recordings.
- Dated tapes
  - 1958
    - Bouscaren/Dunker. (Box 1)
      [Tape 1]
      - Side A: "Brainwashing Experiences," Father Stephen Dunker, St. Louis, Mo., March 1958.
      - Side B: "Soviet Foreign Policy," Anthony Bouscaren, Milwaukee, Wis. February 1960
    - Dunker/Noble.
      [Tape 2]
      - Side A: "Prisoner of the Reds for 9 1/2 Years," John F. Noble.
      - Side B: "Brainwashing," Father Stephen Dunker, St. Louis, Mo. March 1958
  - 1959
    - Arens, Richard
      [Tape 3]
      - Side A: "The Web of Communist Subversion," Richard Arens, Milwaukee, Wis., February 1960.
      - Side B: "Communist Infiltration," Richard Arens, Indianapolis, Ind. October 1959
    - Dunker/Philbrick.
      [Tape 4]
      - Side A: Excerpts, Father Dunker, Rev. Leslie Millin, Richard Arens, Wm. Strube, October 1959.
      - Side B: "Cybernetic Warfare," Herbert Philbr ick
    - Philbrick/Ward.
      [Tape 5]
      - Side A: "Cybernetic Warfare," Herbert Philbrick, St. Louis, Mo., 1959.
      - Side B: "National Suicide by International Agreement," Admiral Chester Ward, Miami, Fla. June 15, 1961
    - Schlafly/Schwarz.
      [Tape 6]
      - Side A: "Is Communism Constitutional," Fred Schlafly, Indianapolis, Ind., September 29, 1959.
      - Side B: "Morals and Motives of Communism," Fred Schwarz
    - Skousen, Cleon
      [Tape 7]
      - Side A: "The Naked Communist," Cleon Skousen, October 1959.
      - Side B: "Communism in Education," Cleon Skousen October 1959
    - Stone, Willis
      [Tape 8]
      - Side A: "The Abolition of Income Taxes" and "The Proposed 23rd Amendment," Willis E. Stone, introduction by Orville Sherwood, Grosse Pointe, Mich., October 21, 1959.
      - Side B: conclusion of lecture
  - 1960
    - Anderson/Philbrick.
      [Tape 9]
      - Side A: Anderson lecture, Detroit, Mich.
      - Side B: "Communist Brainwashing and Cybernetics," Herbert Philbrick, Philadelphia, Pa. November 16, 1960
    - Philbrick/Schlafly.
      [Tape 10]
      - Side A: "Communist Subversion of Youth," Herbert Philbrick, February 1960.
      - Side B: "Communist Fronts and Captive Organizations," Fred Schlafly February 1960
    - Schlafly/Siegrist.
      [Tape 11]
      - Side A: "Communism in the News," Bob Siegrist of WLS, Milwaukee, Wis., February 9, 1960.
      - Side B: "Is Communism Constitutional," Fred Schlafly, Milwaukee, Wis. February 9, 1960
  - 1961
    - Brown/Skousen.
      [Tape 12]
      - Side A: FBI counterspy Julia Brown, Detroit, Mich., April 24, 1964.
      - Side B: Cleon Skousen, Annual meeting of Michigan Farm Bureau, East Lansing, Mich. November 8, 1961
    - Bundy/Thurmond.
      [Tape 13]
      - Side A: Strom Thurmond, Flint, Mich., December 1961.
      - Side B: "Red Infiltration of N.C.C.," Edgar Bundy, Detroit, Mich. October 1961
    - Dodd, Bella
      [Tape 14]
      - Side A: "Counterattack," Bella Dodd September 1, 1961 first talk, questions and answers.
      - Side B: second talk and reminder of questions and answers from first talk
    - Dodd/Philbrick.
      [Tape 15]
      - Side A: "Communism in Education," Bella Dodd, Detroit, Mich., September 1, 1961.
      - Side B: "Communism and Youth," Herbert Philbrick with Ronald Reagan, George Putnam, Roy Rogers, Dale Evans, Pat Boone, Los Angeles, Calif. August 1961
    - Dodd/Schwarz/Dunker.
      [Tape 16]
      - Side A: "Brainwashing," Fred Schwarz and Father Stephen Dunker; "Communist Infiltration of Education," Bella Dodd, Detroit, Mich., September 1, 1961.
      - Side B: Bella Dodd continued
    - Friedman/McKenzie.
      [Tape 17]
      - Side A: Benjamin Friedman, Washington, D.C., 1961.
      - Side B: Rev. McKenzie, Staffin, Rood, Detroit, Mich. January 27, 1962
    - Kershner/Skousen.
      [Tape 18]
      - Side A: Cleon Skousen, Annual meeting of Michigan Farm Bureau, East Lansing, Mich., November 8, 1961.
      - Side B: "Communist Take-over of America," Howard Kershner
    - Schlafly/Wheeler. American Freedom Seminar, January 22, 1961.
      [Tape 19]
      - Side A: "Communist War InSide America, Mrs. J. F. Schlafly, Jr.
      - Side B: Basil Wheeler
    - Schwarz/Ward.
      [Tape 20]
      - Side A: "An Answer to Critics of the Film 'Operation Abolition,'" Fred Schwarz, Miami, Fla., June 15, 1961.
      - Side B: "National Suicide by International Agreement," Admiral Chester Ward, Miami, Fla. June 15, 1961
  - 1962
    - Anderson/Mandel/Schwarz.
      [Tape 21]
      - Side A: Tom Anderson.
      - Side B: Debate, Fred Schwarz and William Mandel, University of California Berkeley February 26, 1962
    - Burke/Skousen.
      [Tape 22]
      - Side A: "Probe," Albert E. Burke; Capt. Eddie, Detroit, Mich., March 1964.
      - Side B: Cleon Skousen, Atlantic City, N.J. 1962
    - Dodd/Dunker.
      [Tape 23]
      - Side A: "Communism, Students and Labor," Bella Dodd, Omaha, Neb., May 10, 1962.
      - Side B: "Brainwashing Experiences in China," Stephen Dunker, St. Louis, Mo.
    - Dodd/Schwarz.
      [Tape 24]
      - Side A: "Inside the Communist Party," Bella Dodd, Seattle, Wash., February 12, 1962.
      - Side B: "How to Debate with Communists and Fellow Travelers," Fred Schwarz, Honolulu, Hawaii, February 2, 1962.
    - Hoover. J. Edgar Hoover address to American Legion National Convention October 9, 1962
    - Hoover/McIntire. Radio talks by Carl McIntire October 24-27, 1962 J. Edgar Hoover, October 9, 1962
      [Tape 26]
    - Mayer/Prussion.
      [Tape 27]
      - Side A: "Brainwashing the Ultimate Weapon," William E, Mayer.
      - Side B: Karl Prussion, Ann Arbor, Mich. October 10, 1963
    - Carl McIntire
      - April 16 and 17 1962
        [Tape 28]
      - April 24 and 25 1962
        [Tape 29]
      - April 30 and May 1, 1962
        [Tape 30]
      - May 2 and 3 1962
        [Tape 31]
    - Noble/Hallinan/Schwarz.
      [Tape 32]
      - Side A: "I was a Slave in Russia," John Noble, Ann Arbor, Mich., January 5, 1963.
      - Side B: Fred Schwarz-Vincent Hallinan debate, San Francisco, Calif. September 15, 1962
  - 1963
    - Morris/Schwarz.
      [Tape 33]
      - Side A: "Communist Threat from Within and Without," Robert Morris, Sacramento, Calif., June 5, 1963.
      - Side B: "Principles and Techniques of Anti-Communist Action," Fred Schwarz June 7, 1963
    - Prussion, Karl.
      - Side A: Karl Prussion, Detroit, Mich., October 6, 1963.
      - Side B: Karl Prussion, Ann Arbor, Mich. October 10, 1963
    - Wilkinson, Frank
      [Tape 35]
      - Side A: Sound track of film shown by Frank Wilkinson; lecture "Abolish the HUAC," Frank Wilkinson.
      - Side B: question and answer period after lecture, Ann Arbor, Mich., March 1, 1963.
        (Tape reel is labeled H. Robert Ingram)
  - 1964
    - "American Opinion Interviews," Ann Arbor, Mich. March 1964 (Box 2)
      [Tape 36]
    - Brown. "Communism vs. Civil Rights," Julia Brown, Detroit, Mich. April 24, 1964
      [Tape 37]
    - Brown/Davidow.
      [Tape 38]
      - Side A: Julia Brown, April 24, 1964.
      - Side B: Larry Davidow May 21, 1964
    - Davidow/Rousselot.
      [Tape 39]
      - Why I am a Conservative, Larry Davidow, Ann Arbor, Mich., May 21, 1964. Rousselot on Civil Rights
    - Decatur. Statement by Catherine Decatur March 1, 1964
      [Tape 40]
    - Greene/Philbrick/Schwarz. Flint Rally November 8, 1964 Herbert Philbrick, Fred Schwarz, Janet Greene
      [Tape 41]
    - Philbrick/Schwarz. Detroit Rally, July 28, 1964.
      [Tape 42]
      - Side A: "Communism and the FBI," Herbert Philbrick.
      - Side B: "Communist Plan for Conquest of the USA," Fred Schwarz
  - 1965
    - Lewis. Fulton Lewis Jr., March 31 and April 1, 1965
      [Tape 43]
- Undated tapes
  - "Christie and Fr. John"
    [Tape 44]
  - Mayor Christopher, 2 tapes
    [Tape 45]
  - Dodd/Judd/Philbrick.
    [Tape 46]
    - Side A: "Internal Security," Thomas Dodd; "Effective Foreign Policy," Walter Judd.
    - Side B: "Communism and Youth," Herbert Philbrick with Ronald Reagan, George Putnam, Roy Rogers, Dale Evans, Pat Boone
  - Drakeford/Ingram.
    [Tape 47]
    - Side A: Robert Ingram.
    - Side B: Dr. Drakeford, 2 speeches
  - Edwards/Lesinski.
    [Tape 48]
    - Side A: Lieutenant Governor T. John Lesinski.
    - Side B; William J. Edwards
  - Fagon. Myron Fagon, 3 tapes
    [Tape 49]
  - Hunter/Roberts.
    [Tape 50]
    - Side A: Major Roberts.
    - Side B: "I Am Only One Person, What Can I Do," Edward Hunter
  - Koch/Skousen.
    [Tape 51]
    - Side A: Fred Koch.
      (CD copy included)
    - Side B: "Communism, Psychiatry and Crime," Cleon Skousen
  - Mayer/Prussion. Karl Prussion; "Brainwashing the Ultimate Weapon," William E. Mayer
    [Tape 52]
  - Mayer/Sluis.
    [Tape 53]
    - Side A: "Brainwashing the Ultimate Weapon," William E. Mayer.
    - Side B: "Communist Economic Warfare," Jost Sluis
  - McIntire/Skousen.
    [Tape 54]
    - Side A: Carl McIntire.
    - Side B: Cleon Skousen.
  - Millin.
    [Tape 55]
    - Side A: "How the Reds Take Over," Leslie Millin.
    - Side B: "Brainwashing Experiences," Leslie Millin(3 copies)
  - Noble/Vaus.
    [Tape 56]
    - Side A: John Noble Detroit lecture.
    - Side B: Jim Vaus, wiretapper for Mickey Cohen gang
  - Noble/Vaus.
    [Tape 58]
    - Side A: "I Was a Slave in Russia," John Noble, Detroit, Mich.
    - Side B: "My Experience in Organized Crime, and Why I Quit," Jim Vaus
  - Oliver/Pittman.
    - Side A: Carter Pittman.
    - Side B: Dr. Oliver
  - Philbrick/Schwarz. Flint Rally.
    [Tape 59]
    - Side A: "Communism and Youth," Herbert Philbrick.
    - Side B: "Extremism, Fascism and Communism," Fred Schwarz
  - Prussion. "In a Communist Cell," Karl Prussion
    [Tape 60]
  - Schwarz. Radio series, 13 short talks on communism by Fred Schwarz
    [Tape 61]
  - Skousen. Cleon Skousen
    [Tape 62]
  - Unlabeled
    [Tape 63]